Register to The Benny Goodman Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Swing Into Spring, April 9, 1958
  - Blues Medley
    - CLOSING BILLBOARD (Box 33, Folder 19)
      Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/GBperc(3)/vl(4)/vla-vc(4)cl/sax/harp
      Transparencies for: vl/vla-vc/perc.
    - SWING INTO SPRING (Box 33, Folder 20)
      Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/cond-prod-P(2)/GBD
  - Swing Into Spring, April 10, 1959
    All instrumental arrangements, unless indicated, are by Ralph Burns. Vocal arrangements are by Buster Davis. The order below follows the sequence in which the arrangements were played, as listed in BG On The Record, page 536. Arrangements held in the New York Public Library Benny Goodman Collection (JPB 80-37) are listed in sequence as well.
    - LET'S DANCE (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Also includes score for extended arrangement. Only 16 measures are indicated in parts.
    - SHOW BILLBOARD (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Parts: cl/saxAATB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/cond-prod-P/PGBD(2)Vperc/vocal group
    - SWING INTO SPRING TAG (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Parts: vocal
    - SPRING THEME/BACH GOES TO TOWN/SWEET CLARINET (Box 34, Folder 4)
      BG No.: 4/6A-B-C
      Score: "Bach Goes To Town" and "Sweet Clarinet" only
      Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/cond-prod-P(2)/PGBD/perc/vocal group(3)
      Key: E flat/B flat/D flat
      These are three arrangements attached together. "Spring Theme" (based on Mozart's Clarinet Quintet in A) is incomplete, lacking only the score.
  - Why Don't You Do Right
    - LIKE YOUNG (Box 34, Folder 5)
      Parts: vocal group(2)
    - MOUNTAIN GREENERY (Box 34, Folder 6)
      BG No.: 8
      Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/cond-prod-P(2)/GBD/perc
    - AH MEN!-AH WOMEN! (Box 34, Folder 7)
      Parts: D/vocals(2)
      Medley for quintet and vocals of: "Sweet Georgia Brown", "I'm Just Wild About Harry", "Sweet Lorraine", "The Gentleman Is A Dope", "When A Woman Loves A Man", and "The Glory Of Love".
    - STRING OF PEARLS (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Parts: cond-prod-P(3)
    - YOU TURNED THE TABLES ON ME (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - ONE O'CLOCK JUMP - NEW (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - S'WONDERFUL "X" (Box 34, Folder 11)
      BG No.: 3
      Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/cond-prod-P(2)/PGBDV
      Also included are parts for "small group" bass and drums. These parts are identical except for key at rehearsal letter H.
  - S'Wonderful/Closing
    - IT WAS WONDERFUL (Box 34, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous (Box 38)
  Included in this box are single parts not belonging to any main entry arrangement, and unidentified fragments of both parts and scores.
- Sound Recordings
  - Instantaneous discs, 120
    Scope and Contents
    The provenance history of these recordings is incomplete. The recordings however feature numerous performances by Goodman along with the various enembles he was part of. The recordings are a mix of radio broadcasts, live performances and studio test pressings. Not all recordings note whether Goodman is performing or not.
    - VII. B. Pretty Lady; Same tune as The Irish Lady; VII.A.Peter Grey, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013508)
    - IV. B. Moosehead Lake; The Low-Down Lonesome Low, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013623)
    - IX. B. Married Me a Wife; Fare Ye Well My Darlin; Wunst I Had an Old Gray Mare, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013524)
    - Run Along You Little Dogies; Adam in the Garden Pinnin Leaves; Hop Up My Ladies, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013532)
    - Little Willie's My Darlin; I'm Worried Now But I Won't Be Worried Long; Take This Hammer, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013540)
    - V. B. Oh My Liver and My Lungs; Sis Joe; Doney Gal; John Henry, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013557)
    - If I Got My Ticket Can I Ride?; Married Me a Wife; Little David Play On Your Harp, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013565)
    - As I Went a Walking One Fine Summer's Evening; If I Got My Ticket Can I Ride?, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013573)
    - I'm Worried Now But I Won't Be Worried Long; Soon One Mornin' Death Come Creepin'; God Don't Like It, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013581)
    - The True Paddy's Song; Santy Anno; The Rich Old Lady, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013599)
    - Tee Roo; Black Jack Davy; The Lady of Carlisle, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126013607)
    - Devilish Mary; Where Have You Been My Good Old Man?; Cod Liver Ile; Lolly Too-Dum, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126526954)
    - The Irish Lady; Little Bird Go Through My Window; Johnny Stiles or a Wild Mustard River, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126526962)
    - Air Check; Carnegie Hall, 1937–1938; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126526970)
      Arrangement
      Resleeved but original sleeve retained
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126526988)
    - Benny Goodman; Unreleased Material; Clarinet Chorus, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126526996)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527002)
    - Benny Goodman; Side 4, Dash 4, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527010)
    - Benny Goodman; Side 3, Dash 4, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527028)
    - R1 Revised, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527036)
    - Benny Goodman; The Sid Caesar Show, 1954 November 1; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527044)
    - Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch. Vinyl. (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527069)
    - Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch. Vinyl. (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527077)
    - Regal Stomp; Benny Goodman, 1969 August 2; 1; 12 inch. Vinyl. (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527085)
    - All of Me, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527093)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527101)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527119)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527127)
    - Revised Side 2, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 138, Item barcode 39002126527135)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527150)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527168)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527176)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527184)
    - Composite Side Two, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527192)
    - [unlabeled], 1937 December; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527200)
    - [unlabeled], 1937 August–1937 September; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527218)
    - Side 2; Dash 3, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527226)
    - Henderson Stomp; Mission to Moscow; Seven Come Eleven; Benny Goodman and His Orchestra, 1943 June 21–1943 December 16; 1; 10 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527234)
    - Rhapsody in Blue; Paul Whiteman, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527242)
    - Perry Como Show, Side 8, 1957 March 23; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527259)
    - Perry Como Show; Side 7, 1957 March 23; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527267)
    - Benny Goodman; Extra Material, 1974 February 28; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527275)
    - Benny Goodman, 1974 February 28; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527283)
    - Benny Goodman, 1974 February 28; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527291)
    - Too Many Tears, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527309)
    - I Want To Be Happy, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527317)
    - Copland Concerto For Clarinet and Orchestra, 1954 December 14; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527325)
    - The New Benny Goodman Sextet, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527341)
    - Benny Goodman Story, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527358)
    - Goody Goody; Sometimes I'm Happy; King Porter Stomp; Alicias Blues; I Got Rhythm; Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527366)
    - Vocal, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527374)
    - Heavy Kissing, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527382)
    - [illegible], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527390)
    - [illegible], undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527408)
    - Spinx; Debussy, undated; 1; 7 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527416)
    - Benny Goodman, 1974 September 3; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527424)
    - Benny Goodman; Reel #8 Side #2; Angel Records, 1936–1937; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527432)
    - Angel Records; Reel #6 Side #1 and #2; Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527440)
    - Angel Records; Reels #3 and #4; Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527457)
    - Angel Records; Reels #1 and #2; Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527465)
    - Angel Records; Reel #7; Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527473)
    - Angel Records; Reel #5; Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527481)
    - Basin St. #4; Benny Goodman, 1936 August 16; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527499)
    - Benny Goodman at Basin St.; Sextet, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527507)
    - LP #1 and #2; Benny Goodman; Basin St., undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527515)
    - Oh Lady Be Good; Ira and George Gershwin; Benny Goodman Quintet; Could This Be Love, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527523)
      V Disc
    - Squeeze Me; Williams-Waller; Let's Fall in Love; Benny Goodman Quintet, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527531)
    - Tour of High Fidelity; Do-It-Yourself Kit, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527549)
      High Flidelity demo disc. Clear disc with card pressed into disc with Goodman's name and address.
    - LP #3; Benny Goodman, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 139, Item barcode 39002126527556)
    - I've Got Rhythm; La Cucaracha; Whispers in the Dark; If I Could Be With You; Marie, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527598)
    - Nobody's Sweetheart; Tiger Rag; Where or When; Tuesday at Ten; Sweet Sue, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527580)
    - Don't You Know Don't You Care; Madhouse; Bach Goes to Town; Twilight in Turkey; I Found a New Baby, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527572)
    - Camel Hop; Ida; Digga Digga Doo; Slipped Disc; Pick-a-Rib, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527606)
    - Sweet Reed; Deep Purple; Dear Old Southland; Clap Hands Here Comes Charlie; Swing Low Sweet Chariot; Once in Awhile, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527614)
    - Benny Goodman; Beyond the Sea, 1950 July 9; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527622)
    - Big John Special, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527630)
    - So Rare; Tea for Two; Tiger Rag; Mr. Ghost Goes to Town; Honeysuckle Rose, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527648)
    - Sometimes I'm Happy; Minnie the Moochers Wedding Day; Bye Bye Pretty Baby; Sing Sing Sing, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527655)
    - The Kingdom of Swing; Pick-A-Rib; Me Myself and I; La Cuccaracha; Dig-Ga Digga Doo; Marie; Coquette; Limehouse Blues; I Wanna Be in Winchell's Column; The Naughty Waltz; In The Shade of the Old Applet Tree; I'd Like to See Soome of Somoa; Caravan; Satan Takes a Holiday; Everybody Loves My Baby; Roll 'Em, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527663)
    - Lady Ellington; Serenade in Blue, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527671)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527689)
    - Hole in One, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527697)
    - Introduction and Ballet from Ramuntcho; Deems Taylor, 1940 March 24; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527705)
    - [illegible], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527713)
    - Elegy for Orchestra; Deems Taylor; Indianapolis Symphony, 1947 March 22; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527721)
    - Self; 1889, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527739)
    - Fanfre; Deem Taylor; Leopold Stokowski, 1944 December 4; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527747)
    - English; Ans. So. Africa #46; Joan Taylor-Einstein; Dub 1+2, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527754)
    - English; Ans. So. Africa #46; Joan Taylor-Einstein; Dub 3+4, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527762)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527770)
    - Deems Taylor's Caesar Great Were Thou, 1941 November 23; 1; 10 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527788)
    - Leon Rothier; May Day Carol; Deems Taylor, 1938 April 24; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527796)
    - Miss Colette D'Arville; Deems Taylor, 1938 December 11; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527804)
    - Frederic March Spot; We The People, 1944 December 10; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527812)
    - Captain; Chesterfield; [illegible], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527820)
    - John Charles Thomas; May Day Carol, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527838)
    - Ave Maria; Deems Taylor; Sung by Gladys Swarthout, 1942 March 1; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527846)
    - [unlabeled], undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527853)
    - Jerry Moore; High Flying Bird; Sea and Sun; Ballad of Birmingham; Quit Your Low Down Ways; Polly Von, 1964 November 9; 1; 12 inch (Box 140, Item barcode 39002126527861)
    - Variations on Sleepers Awake for Two Pianos; Music of Parker Bailey, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527887)
    - Music of Parker Bailey; Jerseywocky; Round of Folk Tunes; Music is My Hobby, 1935–1952; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527895)
    - Horatio Parker; Concerto for Organ and Orchestra; 1902; Bradley Hull; Charles D. Walker, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527903)
    - Horatio Parker Quartette Op. 11; 1885, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527911)
    - Emilio de Gogorza; Mother O'Mine; The Lark Now Leaves Its Wat'ry Next; Emma Eames; Love in May; I Once Had a Sweet Little Doll Dears, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527929)
    - A.D. 1919; Horatio Parker; Part 1; 2; 3, undated; 1; 7 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527937)
    - Horatio Parker; Suite from Fairyland; Richard Korn and Orchestra, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527945)
    - Horatio Parker; Mona: Excerpts; Carnegie Hall Concert; Emma Eames; Emilio de Gogorza, 1961 February 22; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527952)
    - A.D. 1919; Horatio Parker, Side 1 and 2, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527960)
      Poor condition. Delamination.
    - A.D. 1919; Horatio Parker, Part 2 and 4, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527978)
    - Mona's Dream; Horatio Parker, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527986)
    - Horatio Parker; Mona's Dream, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527994)
    - Horatio Parker; A.D. 1919, Part 3 and 4, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126528000)
    - A.D. 1919; Horatio Parker, Part 1 and 2, undated; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126528018)
    - Horatio Parker; Hora Novissima, Side 1 and 2, 1976 January 25; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126528026)
    - Horatio Parker; Hora Novissima, Side 3; Concerto for Organ and Orchestra, Side 4, 1976 January 25; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126528034)
    - Horatio Parker; Hora Novissima, Side 1 and 2, 1976 January 25; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126528042)
    - Horatio Parker; Hora Novissima, Side 3; Concerto for Organ and Orchestra, Side 2, 1976 January 25; 1; 12 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126528059)
      Includes copy of program from 1976-01-25 concert
    - We'll never say goodbye, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126527333)
    - The Dodger, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126013615)
    - My True Love, undated; 1; 10 inch (Box 141, Item barcode 39002126013516)